Stacy Brown-Martin sbrown1031@gmail.com +501.622.1484

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experience includes eleven years of research and teaching in marine science fields spanning population genetics, chemical oceanography, and outreach education programs. Demonstrated proficiency in accurate data collection, experimental design and data analysis, and strong ability to communicate efficiently with employers, coworkers, and students. Proven business startup and managerial skills, both in the U.S. and internationally. Software developer efficient in both front and back end programming.

AREAS OF STRENGTH

* Genomics research and analysis * Fundraising for research grants and charity endeavors

Project management for scientific experiments and entrepreneurial ventures

* Ability to work at sea and in foreign environments * Boat handling skills

* Teaching and mentoring * Microsoft Word, Excel, and Powerpoint * Adobe Photoshop

* HTML 5 * CSS3 * JavaScript * Express.js * React.js * Node.js * MongoDB * MySQL * Git

SKILLS

* Creative * Efficiency oriented * Independent * Organized * Perceptive * Resourceful

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

1) CHEMICAL OCEANOGRAPHER:

RSMAS, NOAA, Scripps, UCSB, Based out of Miami, FL (2002 to 2011)

DOC, pH, alkalinity, and pCO 2 technician on four research cruises crossing the Pacific and Atlantic Collected data and participated in analysis of carbon cycles which contributed to multiple publications regarding global climate change and ocean acidification

Preparation and shipment of equipment for cruises

Independent work as an onboard technician and analyst accumulating ~ 250 total sea days

CONSERVATION GENETICIST: RSMAS, Miami, FL (2004 – 2007)

Research Associate I

Gained thorough knowledge of the various genetic techniques including gelelectrophoresis, PCR, microsatellite development and analysis, and SNP development

Developed micro-satellite loci for the invasive aquatic weed, *Hydrilla averticillata*Conducted population dynamic study on genetic exchange of isolated populations of *Fundulus*Actively participated in lab management; including equipment upkeep, quality control, and aquaria maintenance to ensure a smooth and timely workflow

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (continued)

2) MARINE BIOLOGY TEACHER:

YMCA, Virginia Key Beach, FL (2007 - 2008)

Created, coordinated, and taught a unique marine biology curriculum at the first annual Junior Marine Biology Summer Camp for 100 disadvantaged teenagers

Contributed to art and literacy lesson planning and the snorkel instruction program

Developed a positive rapport with students

Program was the Children's Trust number one summer camp in the nation in 2007

Isabela Oceanographic Institute, Isabela, Galapagos (2008)

Administrative assistant at a field school for undergraduate marine science students Assisted with grant writing and community outreach

3) MARINE BIOLOGIST:

Reef Conservation International, Sapodilla Cayes, Belize (2011)

Taught sustainable development and Caribbean conservation issues to ecotourists

Responsible for teaching and bringing guests on survey dives

Participated in the monitoring and surveys of conch, lobster, whale sharks, lionfish, and turtles

Toledo Institute for Development and the Environment (TIDE), Punta Gorda, Belize (2011 - 2012)

Revised and implemented new methods for surveying conch and lobster in the Port Honduras Marine Reserve

Participated in the development of a new ecotourism based sea turtle monitoring project

Developed the first monitoring protocol for sea cucumber in the reserve

Wrote and published the 2011 Annual Report

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

1) **DIVEMASTER:**

Stuart Cove's, Nassau, Bahamas (2008 - 2009)

Responsible for tourist safety and customer satisfaction at a high demand dive shop with up to 400 customers daily

Certified PADI divemaster, rescue diver, EFR instructor, discover SCUBA instructor, and underwater digital photography instructor

2) BUSINESS STARTUP:

The Boat Cleaning Crew, St. Louis, MO and Miami, FL (1999 – 2008)

Part time independent contractor detailing boats and automobiles Implemented on the job training for up to four employees

2) BUSINESS STARTUP (continued):

Lakeside Market, Festus, MO (2009)

Startup operations for a high grossing convenience store; tasks included establishing distributor relationships, computer networking, staff training and general accounting on Peachtree

Asha's Culture Kitchen, Punta Gorda, Belize (2011 to present)

Own and operate the #1 TripAdvisor rated restaurant in Toledo, Belize Manage all of the advertising, staff training and site design

Kaimani Marine Tours, Punta Gorda, Belize (2017 to present)

Owner operator of ecotourism company

Strong presence in conservation efforts and community development

Oversee all aspects of business development and management

EDUCATION

Washington University; St. Louis, MO

Technical certificate from McKelvey School of Engineering — July 2021 Full stack web development training

University of Miami, College of Arts and Sciences; Miami, FL

Bachelor of Science in biology and marine science, chemistry minor – December 2005 Marine science honors and published senior thesis

School for Field Studies, Center for Marine Resources; Turks and Caicos Islands

Semester of research and study – spring 2004

Research on population structures of elkhorn coral, queen conch, and spiny lobster Thorough knowledge of nomenclature and identification of Caribbean marine species

PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Schelten CK, Brown SD, Gurbisz CB, Kautz B, Lentz JA.(2004) Status of *Acropora palmata* populations off the coast of South Caicos, Turks and Caicos Islands. 57th Gulf and Caribbean Fisheries Institute Proceedings
- 2. Williams DW, Brown SD, Crawford DL. (2008) Contemporary and historical influences on the genetic structure of the estuarine dependent Gulf killifish, *Fundulus grandis*. Marine Ecology Progressive Series 373:111121
- 3. Grajcyk AM, Overholt WA, Cuda JP, Brown SD and Williams DW. (2009) Characterization of microsatellite loci in *Hydrilla verticillata*. Marine Ecology Resources 9:14601559

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

- Mentor for youths at risk (Big Brothers Big Sisters) and disabled adults (Best Buddies)
- Captain of multiple fundraising teams for Relay for Life, AID's Walk, and Toys for Tots
- Member of Belize Tourism Industry Association